Name, FirstParagraph

":mentalKLINIK,http://ivde.net/artists/mentalklinik_1/biography</Address>
:mentalKLINIK is an artist duo from <Location>Istanbul</Location> composed of Yasemin Baydar (B.<Date>1972</Date>, İstanbul) and Birol Demir (B.1967, <Location>Ankara</Location>) who began their collaborative works in <Date>1998</Date>, forming an open laboratory to reconsider process, production and presentation. Their studio has functioned as a space for dialogue and they enrich their process by engaging other artists and professionals in fields ranging from chemistry to industrial engineering.
The collaborative resist the limitations posed by a singular vocabulary or style and craft material and digital technologies into works that seem to belong to anticipated aesthetics. Their works range from immersive time based works and installations to sculptures and objects that thwart categorization. Publications often accompany projects to reflect their interactive process, and include a form of documentation seeking to explore concepts and contexts pertaining to emotions, behaviour, viewpoints and senses.
Their work also engages the public in live and embodied installations. Terribly Jolly (<Location>Istanbul</Location>, <Date>2013</Date>) for example is a pop-up dance club contained within a small red curtained room that begins at nine am and lasts just thirty minutes, folding together the time of work and leisure to cut short any possibility of shared pleasure. By contrast FRESHCUT (<Organization>Museum of Applied Arts</Organization>, <Location>Vienna</Location>, <Date>2013</Date>) invites the audience to cut and arrange a massive installation of flowers, transforming them into actors in an augmented cinematic reality. "

"Abbas Akhavan,http://www.thethirdline.com/artists/abbas-akhavan/biography/</Address>
Abbas Akhavan&apos;s practice ranges from site-specific ephemeral installations to drawing, video and performance. The domestic sphere, as a forked space between hospitality and hostility, has been an ongoing area of research in Abbas&apos; work. More recent works have shifted focus, wandering onto spaces just outside the home – the garden, the backyard, and other domesticated landscapes.
Residencies include Foundation Marcelino Botin with Mona Hatoum (<Location>Spain</Location>), <Organization>Le Printemps de Septembre (France)</Organization>, <Location>Trinity Square</Location> Video, <Location>Western Front</Location>, and <Location>Fogo Islands</Location> (<Location>Canada</Location>), The <Organization>Watermill Center (USA)</Organization>, and The <Organization>Delfina Foundation (Dubai</Organization>, <Location>UAE</Location> &amp; <Location>London</Location>, <Location>UK</Location>). Recent exhibitions include: &apos;Variations on a <Location>Garden</Location>&apos;, Galerie Mana, <Location>Istanbul</Location> (<Date>2013</Date>); &apos;Study for a <Location>Garden</Location>&apos;, <Organization>Delfina Foundation</Organization>, <Location>London</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>); &apos;Tactics for Here &amp; Now&apos;, <Location>Bucharest</Location> Biennale, <Location>Bucharest</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>); &apos;Tools for Conviviality&apos; <Organization>Power Plant</Organization>, <Location>Toronto</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>); &apos;Beacon&apos;, Darling Foundry, <Location>Montreal</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>); &apos;Phantomhead&apos;, Performa 11, <Location>New York</Location> (<Date>2011</Date>); &apos;Seeing is Believing&apos;, <Organization>KW Institute</Organization> for Contemporary Art, <Location>Berlin</Location> (<Date>2011</Date>). Abbas is the recipient of Kunstpreis <Location>Berlin</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>), and Abraaj Captial Art Prize (<Date>2014</Date>).
He lives and works in <Location>Toronto</Location>, <Location>Canada</Location>."

"Abbas Kiarostami
Filmmaker,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/k/kiarostami-abbas</Address>
Abbas Kiarostami graduated from university with a degree in fine arts before starting work as a graphic designer. Later joining the Centre for Intellectual Development of Children and Young Adults he initiated a film section, which launched his career as a filmmaker at the age of 30. An active filmmaker since <Date>1970</Date>, Kiarostami has been involved in over forty films including shorts and documentaries. Among his most critically successful works as director are what came to be known as the Koker Trilogy (Where Is the Friend&apos;s Home?, <Date>1987</Date>, And Life Goes On (a.k.a. Life and Nothing More, <Date>1992</Date>) and Through the Olive Trees, <Date>1994</Date>), A Taste of Cherry (<Date>1997</Date>), The Wind Will Carry Us (<Date>1999</Date>) and his innovative <Date>2008</Date> film Shirin which was screened at Past of the Coming Days. Amongst many other honours, Kiarostami has been awarded a Palme d&apos;Or, <Location>Cannes</Location> Festival (<Date>1997</Date>), Silver Lion, <Location>Venice</Location> Film Festival (<Date>1999</Date>), Gold Leopard of Honour, Locarno Film Festival (<Date>2005</Date>) and Glory to the Filmmaker Award, <Location>Venice</Location> Film Festival (<Date>2008</Date>). His <Date>2010</Date> film Certified Copy was screened that year at <Location>Cannes</Location> earning its lead, Juliette Binoche, a best actress award.
Abbas Kiarostami was born in <Location>Tehran</Location> in <Date>1940</Date>. He is also a poet, photographer, painter and illustrator.
<Date>November 2010</Date>
"

"Abdelfattah Kilito
Writer,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/k/kilito-abdelfattah</Address>
Esteemed writer and academic Abdelfattah Kilito was born in <Date>1945</Date> in <Location>Rabat</Location>, <Location>Morocco</Location>. 
His lecture titled Thou Shalt Not Translate Me, followed on from the topic of his well-known book Thou Shalt Not Speak My Language ( <Organization>Sysracuse University Press</Organization>, <Date>2002</Date>). In his work Kilito &apos;. . . disrupts dominant modes of Arabic literary scholarship and challenges us . . . to reexamine contemporary notions of translation, bilingualism, postcoloniality, the pedagogy of world literature, and the discipline of comparative literature.&quot;*
Kilito studied at the Faculty of Arts and Human Sciences in <Location>Rabat</Location> and obtained his doctorate on the narrative and cultural patterns in the works of Alhmdani and AlHariri from the new University of Sorbonne in <Date>1982</Date>. He has been a Professor of Arts at <Organization>Mohamed V University</Organization>, <Location>Rabat</Location>, since 1968 and Visiting Professor at several European and <Origin>American</Origin> universities, including the <Organization>University of Bordeaux</Organization> and the Sorbonne, the Collège de <Location>France</Location>, <Location>Princeton</Location> University and <Organization>Harvard University</Organization>. Kilito has received several literary awards among which are the Great <Origin>Moroccan</Origin> Award (<Date>1989</Date>); Atlas Award (<Date>1996</Date>); <Organization><Origin>French</Origin> Academy</Organization> Award (<Date>1996</Date>); Sultan Al Owais Prize, Criticism &amp; Literature Studies (<Date>2006-06</Date>). He is the author of both fiction and literary criticism with some of his works translated into other languages including <Origin>English</Origin>, <Origin>French</Origin>, <Origin>German</Origin>, <Origin>Spanish</Origin> and <Origin>Italian</Origin>.
Works (selected):La Querelle des images, <Location>Casablanca</Location>, Editions Eddif, <Date>1995</Date>.La Langue d’Adam;<Location>Casablanca</Location>, Ed. Toubkal, <Date>1995</Date>.En quête, <Location>Montpellier</Location>, Editions Fata Morgana, <Date>1999</Date>.Le Cheval de Nietzsche, Editions Le Fennec, <Date>2007</Date>.Les Arabes et l’art du récit, Editions Sindbad-Actes Sud, <Date>2009</Date>.Dites-moi le songe, Editions Sindbad-Actes Sud, <Date>2010</Date>.
* Quoted from the Translator&apos;s Introduction to Thou Shalt Not Speak My Language by Waïl S. Hassan, <Organization>Syracuse University Press</Organization>, 2002<Date>October 2010</Date>
""

Abdelkader Benchamma,http://edgeofarabia.com/artists/abdelkader-benchamma</Address>
Abdelkader Benchamma was born in <Date>1975</Date> in <Location>France</Location> to <Origin>Algerian</Origin> parents. He graduated from the <Organization>École Supérieure des Beaux Arts de Paris</Organization> in <Date>2003</Date>. Benchamma was part of the <Date>2009</Date> Printemps de Septembre in <Location>Toulouse</Location>, curated by Christian Bernard, and Told Untold Retold at the <Organization>Mathaf Museum</Organization>, <Location>Qatar</Location>. In <Date>April 2011</Date>, his solo show, Dark Matter, was held at the <Organization>Galerie du Jour</Organization>. Abdelkader Benchamma is represented by <Organization>Galerie du Jour</Organization> Agnes B., <Location>Paris</Location>, and <Organization>AND Galeria</Organization>, <Location>Barcelona</Location>.&#160;"

"Abdul Ghafur Sheikh,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdulghafursheikh.html</Address>
Abdul Ghafur Sheikh was a muslim student at <Organization>Harvard Business School</Organization> who travelled to <Location>Mecca</Location> and published his experience and colour pictures as the lead story From <Location>America</Location> to <Location>Mecca</Location> on Airborne Pilgrimage in the <Date>July 1953</Date> edition of National Geographic.
"

"Abdul Qadir al-Rassam,http://www.encyclopedia.mathaf.org/en/bios/Pages/Abdul-Qadir-al-Rassam.aspx</Address>
Abdul Qadir al-Rassam (<Date>1882 - 1952</Date>) was part of the first generation of modern <Origin>Iraqi</Origin> painters. He stands at the core of a group of artists trained in <Location>Istanbul</Location> who brought their artistic knowledge back to their home country. This group of soldier-artists is credited with introducing easel painting to <Location>Iraq</Location> at the turn of the century. Working in a realist style, al-Rassam is known for his sweeping landscapes, immaculate portraits, and faithful portrayals of everyday life in <Location>Iraq</Location>. He is one of the most prominent and prolific painters in <Location>Iraq</Location>&apos;s modern art history and his work heavily influenced the generations that followed.
Al-Rassam was among a group of <Origin>Iraqi</Origin> officers to study military science and art in <Location>Istanbul</Location>. He began his education around 1904 when the Ottoman Empire was still the main power in the region. As part of his education in <Location>Istanbul</Location>, al-Rassam and his classmates were required to produce paintings or drawings for military use. These images adhered to a strict European academic style. Eager to cultivate their new skill, these officers sought out private art training. Al-Rassam himself studied under a number of prominent painters living in <Location>Istanbul</Location> who worked in contemporary <Origin>French</Origin> styles. Although he is most recognizable as an oil painter, al-Rassam experimented at this time with watercolors representing <Location>Istanbul</Location> with its crowds and markets. Even at this early stage in his career, the painter showed expert skill and a conscientious eye. Al-Rassam&apos;s ambitions were interrupted by the outbreak of WWI. Directly following the war, when the group of soldier-artists returned to <Location>Iraq</Location>, al-Rassam again took up easel painting. Along with his colleagues, he focused on landscapes, military scenes, and archaeological sites. 
An important characteristic of this initial generation was their desire to stimulate awareness and appreciation of the arts amongst the <Origin>Iraqi</Origin> population. Al-Rassam taught painting lessons out of his studio in <Location>Baghdad</Location> and encouraged young artists to continue their art training abroad. Due to this early artistic proselytizing, al-Rassam became hugely influential to the following generations of artists. The painter&apos;s interest in promoting art awareness was further realized when he became an honorary member of the <Organization>Society of the Friends</Organization> of Art, a group that sought to cultivate public interest in art making and to enhance their own skill through interaction.    
Utilizing the same academic style as his early colleagues, al-Rassam painted with a crisp realism capturing vistas of the <Origin>Iraqi</Origin> countr​yside. The clarity found in oil paints is employed to its fullest advantage by the artist, who is known for his mastery of perspective and detail. He oftentimes painted panoramic views of historical sites along the <Location>Tigris River</Location>. The ruins of Ctesiphon or the Great Mosque of Samarra were particularly notable representations in al-Rassam&apos;s oeuvre. Indeed the <Location>Tigris River</Location> was itself the central theme of many of al-Rassam&apos;s canvases. Winding as it recedes through an expert use of atmospheric perspective, the river and the activities surrounding it compose a vast, yet serene, landscape.
Al-Rassam was also to a lesser extent a portraitist. One of his well-known portraits is of Mohamed Darouich al-Allousi, completed in <Date>1924</Date>. The bearded sitter gazes out at the viewer with a directed stare. He is set against a background of clouds that are ever-present in most of al-Rassam&apos;s canvases. The subtleties of the face show the painter&apos;s mastery of modeling and the poignant gaze reflect his skill as a keen observer. The portrait exhibits the same attention to clarity and detail as al-Rassam&apos;s landscapes.
A collection of al-Rassam&apos;s works was held at the <Organization>Pioneers Museum</Organization> in <Location>Baghdad</Location> and the <Origin>Iraqi</Origin> <Organization>Museum of Modern Art</Organization> until the destruction and the looting of the collection of the museum in <Date>2003</Date>. He also created a mural for the entrance of a movie theater in <Location>Baghdad</Location>, The Royal Cinema. This was the first large-scale work of art to be displayed on a public building. Later in his life, the artist travelled to <Location>Italy</Location>, <Location>France</Location>, <Location>Germany</Location>, and <Location>England</Location> to expand his knowledge of art.
"

"Abdulaziz Ashour,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdulazizashour.html</Address>
Abdulaziz Ashour (<Date>1962</Date>) is from old <Location>Jeddah</Location> and has worked many years as an employee of the <Organization>Ministry of Energy</Organization>. Some of his imagery reflects this environment. He is a painter and participated in the <Organization>Edge of Arabia</Organization> exhibition in <Location>London</Location> in <Date>2008</Date> where he showed two acrylic works on canvas of large size (160 x 160 cm) titled Soft White I &amp; II. (<Date>2009</Date>).Another look at Ashours work, who stands out among other abstract painters because of both a vision of beauty that has maturity and a truthfulness to his own experience, was allowed at the Nabatt exhibition in <Location>Shanghai</Location> in <Date>2010</Date>.
"

"Abdulhalim Radwi
Radawi,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdulhalimradwi.html</Address>
Abdulhalim Radwi (<Date>1939-2006</Date>) (also: Radawi) from <Location>Makkah</Location> was a painter, poet and sculptor in <Location>Jeddah</Location> and a pioneer of contemporary arts in <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location>. He was one of the first <Origin>Saudi</Origin>&apos;s to go abroad for an art education and held a <Organization>BA</Organization> degree from the <Organization>Academy of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Rome</Location> (<Date>1964</Date>).
Radwi started his career as a teacher of fine arts in <Location>Makkah</Location> but became much involved with the government of arts. From <Date>1968-1974</Date> he was director of the <Location>Jeddah</Location> centre for fine arts and later (<Date>1980-1992</Date>) director-general of the culture and arts city of <Location>Jeddah</Location>.
In <Date>1973</Date> Radwi spent time in <Location>Madrid</Location> were he was action director of the <Organization>Association of Arab</Organization> artists. In <Date>1979</Date> Radwi graduated from the royal arts academy in <Location>Madrid</Location>. He was awarded many art prizes and honours while he spent much time abroad organizing as many as 105 exhibitions. 
His family maintain a website with some of his work and say it can also be seen in museums of modern art in <Location>Jordan</Location>, <Location>Brazil</Location>, Marocco, <Location>Spain</Location> and <Location>Tunisia</Location>.
In Riyadh Hewar Gallery in <Date>2008</Date> offer watercolours and an oil painting. Christie&apos;s at an international modern &amp; contemporary art sales in <Location>Dubai</Location> on <Date>October 30, 2008</Date> will auction Still Life (<Date>1956</Date>). Radwi signed this work twice: in &apos;latin&apos; on the lower left and in arabic on the lower right.
Radwi&apos;s paintings dealt mostly with <Origin>Saudi</Origin> lifestyle and he is said to have believed that <Origin>Saudi</Origin> artists must always keep an eye on their national identity. His two personal favorite paintings were thus Recitation of Quran, which won a prize at the <Date>1988</Date> Biennale in <Location>Spain</Location>, and Old Buildings in <Location>Makkah</Location>, which he refused to sell for half a million <Origin>Saudi</Origin> riyals and kept in his personal museum in <Location>Jeddah</Location>.
"

"Abdullah Al Saadi,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/s/saadi-abdullah-al</Address>
 
b. 1967, Khorfakkan, <Location>United Arab Emirates</Location>
Lives and works in Khorfakkan
Abdullah Al Saadi is a <Date>1993</Date> graduate of the <Organization>United Arab Emirates University</Organization>, Al Ain and holds a <Organization>BA</Organization> degree in <Origin>English</Origin> Literature. <Date>From 1994 to 1996</Date> he studied <Origin>Japanese</Origin> painting at <Organization>Kyoto Seika University</Organization> in <Location>Japan</Location>. Al Saadi’s work ranges from painting, drawing, the creation of lengthy artist’s notebooks, to the collection and systemic categorisation of found objects, and the invention of new alphabets. A great affinity with nature and rural life informs his practice, which explores the changing environment as well as personal and cultural history. He has exhibited internationally and regionally including; Emirati Expressions: Realised at <Organization>Manarat Al Saadiyat</Organization>, <Location>Abu Dhabi</Location>, <Location>UAE</Location>(<Date>2013</Date>); Body Art and Performance in <Location>the Gulf</Location> Area: 16 artists at <Organization>New York University Abu Dhabi</Organization>, <Location>UAE</Location> (<Date>2013</Date>); <Organization>Sharjah Biennial</Organization> 10, <Location>Sharjah</Location>, <Location>UAE</Location> (<Date>2011</Date>); 54th International Art Exhibition of the <Organization>Venice Biennale</Organization>, <Location>Venice</Location>, <Location>Italy</Location>(<Date>2011</Date>); ADACH Platform at the 53rd International Art Exhibition of the <Organization>Venice Biennale</Organization>, <Location>Venice</Location>, <Location>Italy</Location> (<Date>2009</Date>); Languages of the Desert at <Organization>Kunstmuseum Bonn</Organization>, <Location>Germany</Location> (<Date>2005</Date>); the 26th <Organization>São Paulo Biennial</Organization>, <Location>Sao</Location> Paolo, <Location>Brazil</Location> (<Date>2004</Date>); <Organization>Sharjah Biennial</Organization> 5, <Location>Sharjah</Location>, <Location>UAE</Location> (<Date>2003</Date>), 5/U.A.E., The Art of the Five from the <Location>United Arab Emirates</Location> at the Ludwig Forum for International Art, Aachen, <Location>Germany</Location> (<Date>2002</Date>).
"

"Abdullah Al-Mazrook,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdullahalmazrook.html</Address>
Abdullah Al-Mazrook is a mixed media artist who has a <Organization>BA</Organization> in Fine Art from a school in <Location>Atlanta</Location>, <Location>Georgia</Location>. He appears to have been active in Youth Welfare in Qatif giving courses in art (history). In <Date>1975</Date> he respresented <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location> at an Arab Youth Exhibition in <Location>Libya</Location>. In <Date>the 1990s</Date> he showed his work from the <Location>USA</Location> to <Origin><Location>Bangladesh</Location></Origin> and <Location>China</Location>. In <Date>2000</Date> The Arab Heritage Gallery in Al-Khobar exhibited his mixed media Desert Rainbow series.
"

"Abdullah Al-Ogaili ,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdullaalogaili.html</Address>
Abdullah Al-Ogaili is a professional photographer who&apos;s work was selected for the Al Mohtaraf publication Young <Origin>Saudi</Origin> Lenses (<Date>2011</Date>). A large and colorful image of Al Salam Park in <Location>Riyadh</Location> and a smaller still life of four traditional pots both celebrated the decorative side of human life. A similar observation when studying work the artist has posted on Flickr. Finding beauty in everyday spaces, such as in a hospital operation room, is an art not many people master. Al-Ogaili does however. Add a slight touch of color to your life and the artist might come and take your portrait. He has won at least one prize abroad with his portrait photography and shows a number of serious portraits of shaikhs and business leaders online. The portrait that we enjoyed the most was that of a man and a collection of parrots. (AH, <Date>8 May 2013</Date>).
"

"Abdullah Al-Othman,http://edgeofarabia.com/artists/abdullah-al-othman</Address>
Born <Date>1985</Date> in <Location>Riyadh</Location>, <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location>"

"Abdullah Al-Shaikh,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdullahalshaikh.html</Address>
Greenbox dictionary of <Origin>Saudi Arabian</Origin> artistsHome&#160;&#160; Index
"

"Abdullah Hammas,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdullahhammas.html</Address>
Abdullah Hammas (Abha, 1953) was a prepschool art teacher for 31 years after graduating from the <Organization>Riyadh Institute of Arts</Organization> in <Date>1973</Date>. He is one of seven artists supported by the <Organization>Al Mansouria Foundation</Organization> and is credited by them to be among the first painters to have pushed the limits of traditional and decorative painting and to have embarked on an abstract quest to link colours and materials to his homeland.
The square paintings he mostly makes are colourful and sometimes adapted to the venture where they are sold. In Riyadh they are mature and serious in nature and do not venture beyond abstract forms. In Al-Khobar he is on show in the Arab Heritage Gallery with a slightly later birthdate (<Date>1955</Date>) and with brighter colours, clearer lines and human forms. There too are for sale his Abha panels which are vertical columns measuring 30x245 cm that contain 8 small but very bright paintings. 
Hammas has had many personal exhibitions in galleries in KSA and has also ventured out to <Location>Paris</Location> and <Location>Rabat</Location>. His paintings have found their way to public collections in the <Location>Middle East</Location>, <Location>Europe</Location> and the <Location>U.S.A.</Location>
"

"Abdullah Idrees,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdullahidrees.html</Address>
Abdullah Idrees is a painter from <Location>Jeddah</Location> who sells his oil works at Hewar Gallery in <Location>Riyadh</Location> and was according to Arab News a well known figure at a <Date>2003</Date> exhibition when they discussed a painting of his: 
&quot;a striking textural painting by Abdullah Idrees, at first seemingly of a decorated door, shows panels with a face behind it. The thought behind the piece is to raise the question whether the figure is evaluating the viewer from behind a cultural barrier or whether the viewer is sympathizing with what he assumes is a prisoner. If there is a consistency in the exhibition, it is the idea of duality, alternative viewpoints and conflicting though reconcilable perspectives.&quot;
"

"Abdullah Nawawi,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdullahnawawy.html</Address>
Abdullah Nawawi is a painter of colourful abstraction from <Location>Jeddah</Location>, who is (<Date>2009</Date>) manager of the <Organization>Plastic Art Committee</Organization> of the <Organization>Ministry of Culture</Organization> and <Organization>Information</Organization>&apos;s <Organization><Origin>Saudi Arabian</Origin> Association of Arts</Organization> and <Organization>Culture</Organization>. His education is <Origin>American</Origin> and in arts and ceramics. Interviewed by the <Location>Yemen</Location> Observer he explains his work as lines moving up and down and remembering moments of great joy and sadness. He also stated that his country needed two large gallery&apos;s in <Location>Riyadh</Location> and <Location>Jeddah</Location> to build permanent collections. he compliments the government fro financing artists and buying art for embassies abroad.
"

"Abdulmajid Ali Al-Jarouf,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdulmajidalialjarouf.html</Address>
Abdulmajid Ali Al-Jarouf is a painter from Saihat. He has a <Organization>BA</Organization> (<Date>1974</Date>) in architecture from the <Organization>University of Petroleum</Organization> and Minerals in <Location>Dahran</Location> in which year he was also awarded for the general presidency of the Youth Welfare art exhibition and participated in <Location>Libya</Location>. In <Date>2003</Date> he had a solo exhibition in The Atelier of <Location>Jeddah</Location> and in <Date>2004</Date> joined a group event in <Location>the Gulf</Location> Club in Saihat.On the website listed below he has a gallery of his work which includes drawings from his sketchbook. I selected the collage like paintings here because they betray knowledge and adaption of such artists as Michaelangelo and Delacroix. (<Date>2009</Date>).
"

"Abdulnasser Al-Amri,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdulnasseralamri.html</Address>
Abdulnasser Al-Amri is a name which was used by Abdulnasser Gharem (see there) when he was showing work of a more traditional style. In <Date>May 2008</Date> his painting of the Kaaba (Composition II) was the winner of the <Organization>BMG Foundation</Organization> sponsored &apos;Art for Life&apos; exhibition at the <Organization>Jeddah Hilton Hotel</Organization> and went to a charity auction in <Location>London</Location> during <Location>the Gulf</Location> Polo Cup. Although Al-Amri painted he told Arab News he concentrates on the concept of his painting and thinks it is unfortunate that not more styles of modern art are exhibited in <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location>. (<Date>2009</Date>).
"

"Abdulnasser Gharem&apos;s,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdulnassergharem.html</Address>
Abdulnasser Gharem&apos;s (<Date>1973</Date>) mission is to restore behaviour to a higher standard, remembered from the past, while taking into account new technologies and insights. The artist from the town of <Location>Khamis</Location> Mushait is a luitenant-colonel of artillery (now in administration), who aims at the brains and not the bone structure of life&apos;s realities. Do not put your trust in concrete, when planning battles of the future, is what Gharem says by selecting his own ground to fire from with weapons of his choice. The training shows. The &apos;art people&apos; call it performance art. People of performance might call it art of survival.
Gharem entered the field at the <Location>Sharjah</Location> <Date>2007</Date> biennial documenting a &apos;survival&apos; performance Flora and Fauna (<Date>2006</Date>) in which he wrapped himself in plastic with a tree on a busy road in the town of <Location>Abha</Location>. He stayed in his greenhouse for several hours living of the oxygen that the tree was meant to produce. The foreign imported Conocarpus Erectus tree is much used in city landscaping in the <Location>Middle East</Location> and elsewhere, but is said to have a disastrous effect on the local tree population. Dealing directly with ecological concerns of urban planning the performance in a much broader sense may have reflected on the dangers of thoughtless adoption of foreign ideas.
&apos;People at first thought he was crazy,&apos; is what Gharem told Henry Hemming in an interview for the <Organization>Edge of Arabia</Organization> (<Date>2008</Date>) exhibition. But then they started to appreciate his operations on the roads of <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location>. &apos;Their minds are not closed so they came over to ask about it.&apos; Reforming people&apos;s ideas about art away from copying Italians may be collateral damage his work inflicts.
Another maneuvre of speed and impact was in support not of flora but of Homo Erectus himself. In Manzoa (<Date>2007</Date>) Gharem moved himself around for a day and night in a so called &apos;unorganized residential district&apos; from which both the residents and houses were to be removed for new development. The name of the performance is Arabic for &apos;removal.&apos; It was written on the houses to announce their fate and that of their residents and the artist had it written on his shirt during the performance.
From chance of seeing a broken bridge and learning its history Gharem welded his conceptually most voluptuous work. Al-Siraat was made in the night of <Date>August 19, 2007</Date> when the artist and his assistents covered the whole bridge with one word: al-siraat (the path). The bridge, which is in a ravine in the Tihama region, had been abandoned since it collapsed in <Date>1982</Date>. Its tragic history is that it was used by people, trusting the concrete, as a refuge to shelter from an expected flash flood. From the idea that even concrete roads and bridges can&apos;t be trusted Gharem crossed over to associate the bridge with &apos;the path&apos; in the spiritual sense of the word. &apos;It is about the choices you make in life, and whether or not you follow the straight path,&apos; is what he said about it. The work was documented by photography and in a video with a touch of irony.
Al-Siraat became part of a controversy in the <Origin>British</Origin> press when it was reported that the work had not been included in the <Organization>Edge of Arabia</Organization> exhibition by a decision unclearly defined as having been taken by either a sponsor, guest curators or The <Organization>School of Oriental and African Studies</Organization>.
In both a visual and conceptual parallel to Al Siraat Gharem produced an alternative work of art for the exhibition intended to convey a similar message. For his Restored Behavior (<Date>2008</Date>) series the artist went on a humoristic adventure of subverting bureaucracy by buying in shops all over <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location> as many office stamps as he could find. Taking out the rubber letters and numbers, glueing them on boards and then painting over them a yellow road line he created anew an image of &apos;the path.&apos; Not having yourself stamped but painting your own way over stamps is not unlike &apos;not trusting concrete.&apos; In the paintings the bridge crossing the ravine was changed by Gharem into a Pedestrian Crossing. And like the bridge the crossing collapsed: the two stripes of the Zebra contained an image of the Twin Towers at the moment of impact of the second airplane. As a final salvo of his serious intentions Gharem produced an oversized and useable stamp which read in both hope and irony and in both Arabic and <Origin>English</Origin>: &apos;Have a bit of commitment, Amin.&apos; With it were three road lights to guide you in the dark. Using science in darkness may be the concept.
His motto: &apos;I will&apos;
"

"Abdulnasser Gharem,http://nadour.org/artists/abdulnasser-gharem/</Address>
Art of Survival – this stands as a kind of preliminary statement to all the work of this artist born in <Date>1973</Date> in <Location>Khamis Mushait</Location>, <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location>. Abdulnasser Gharem is surely the only artist to be both a leading figure on his country’s emerging art scene and a major in the <Origin>Saudi</Origin> army.
His story began in <Date>2003</Date> when Abdulnasser Gharem, an army recruit, enrolled in the Al-Miftaha <Location>Arts Village</Location> in <Location>Abha</Location>, <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location>. Founded a few years earlier by Ahmed Mater, this institution soon became the nerve centre of the new art scene that was represented in the <Date>2004</Date> exhibition Shattah, which captured the renewal of the <Origin>Saudi Arabian</Origin> scene.
From now on, Gharem began using the street as his studio, working in response to his local context. In numerous performances and site-specific installations he drew attention to ecological, geographical, urban and societal issues, recording his actions on video or in photographs. At the same time he was working on a series of stamp paintings in which major events are juxtaposed with the excesses of a bureaucratic system that seems capable of expressing itself only by rubberstamping.
Acclaimed by international critics and now recognised in the <Location>Middle East</Location>, his work was presented at the 53rd <Organization>Venice Biennale</Organization> in <Date>2009</Date> and at the 8th <Organization>Sharjah Biennial</Organization> in <Date>2007</Date>. His works have been seen in <Location>Venice</Location>, <Location>London</Location>, <Location>Berlin</Location> and <Location>Riyad</Location> as part of exhibitions organised by <Organization>Edge of Arabia</Organization>.
"

"Abdulrahman Soliman,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-abdulrahmansoliman.html</Address>
Abdulrahman Soliman (<Date>1963</Date>) exhibits paintings of a mysterious dark visison at Hewar. His work has featured at an <Date>2002</Date> exhibition Artistes contemporains <Origin>Saoudiens</Origin> at the Institute du Monde Arabe.
"

"Adam Henein,http://www.encyclopedia.mathaf.org/en/bios/Pages/Adam-Henein.aspx</Address>
Adam Henein was born in <Location>Cairo</Location> into a family of silversmiths from Asyut and grew up in the neighborhood of Bab al-Shaariyya. He was eight years old when he discovered the <Organization><Origin>Egyptian</Origin> Museum of Antiquities</Organization> during a class visit, which he would later recall as a turning point in his life. At the age of twenty, he decided to become a sculptor and joined the <Organization>School of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Cairo</Location>. After he graduated in <Date>1953</Date>, he traveled to Upper <Location>Egypt</Location> and spent several months at the <Location>Luxor</Location> Atelier established in <Date>1941</Date> by the Alexandrian painter and diplomat Mohammed Naghi (<Date>1888 - 1956</Date>) to promote the study of ancient <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> art as part of the curriculum of art schools in <Location>Egypt</Location>.
In 1957, he received a scholarship for two years to pursue his studies at the <Organization>Academy of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Munich</Location>. During one of his exhibitions in <Date>1960</Date>, he met the anthropologist Afaf al-Dib, who became his wife and supporter as both manager and critic at the beginning of his career. Henein established his home and studio in <Date>1968</Date> in a mud brick house built by architect Ramsis Wissa Wassef (<Date>1911 - 1974</Date>) in the village of <Location>Harraniyya</Location>. In <Date>1971</Date>, Henein and his wife moved to <Location>Paris</Location>, where they stayed for twenty-five years. During that period, he dedicated himself to his art in his studio in the fifteenth arrondissement near Porte de Sèvres. By the time he returned to <Location>Egypt</Location> in <Date>1996</Date>, Henein was an internationally recognized artist. <Date>From 1989 to 1998</Date>, he worked with the <Organization>Ministry of Culture</Organization> in restoring the Sphinx in Giza. In <Date>1996</Date>, he founded the <Organization>Aswan International</Organization> Sculpture Symposium, an annual workshop and exhibition inviting sculptors from around the world to experiment and create works from the local granite.
Adam Henein is one of the most prominent contemporary sculptors of the Arab World. Throughout his career, he produced a considerable number of large and small-scale pieces, using a variety of materials, such as granite, bronze, plaster, limestone and terracotta. His early works embody the graceful solidity of ancient <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> statuary and express a sense of simplicity in the treatment of mass and volumes. They recall ancient sculptures, such as the scribe commonly known as the &quot;Sheikh el-Balad,&quot; now at the <Organization><Origin>Egyptian</Origin> Museum of Antiquities</Organization>, as well as the works of Mahmoud Mokhtar (<Date>1891 - 1934</Date>). During the 1960&apos;s, Henein sculpted a series of animals, such as birds, cats, dogs, owls, goats, horses and donkeys, expressing just their minimal and essential lines and features. 
The beginning of the <Date>1970</Date>&apos;s marked an important evolution in his art, as a result of being exposed to the work of modern sculptors in <Location>Paris</Location>, such as Brancusi. Even though Henein never belonged to a specific movement, he was inspired by their freedom of interpretation. During the <Date>1980</Date>&apos;s, abstract forms, pure volumes and the dynamic of movement characterize his sculptures, centered on the themes of sun and moon disks, as well as vertical ascension. In the <Date>1990</Date>&apos;s, he worked on several outdoor large-scale sculptures, including The Ship, conceived as a metaphorical alternative to the museum space. Overall, his work embodies a sense of simple monumentality and timelessness.
Henein has held many individual exhibitions in <Location>Cairo</Location>, <Location>Alexandria</Location>, <Location>Amsterdam</Location>, <Location>London</Location>, <Location>Paris</Location>, and <Location>Rome</Location>, and participated in numerous group exhibitions around the world. His works can be seen at his Museum in <Location>Harraniyya</Location> inaugurated in <Date>January 2014</Date>, the <Organization>Museum of <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> Modern</Organization> Art in <Location>Cairo</Location>, as well as at Mathaf: <Organization>Arab Museum of Modern Art</Organization> in <Location>Doha</Location>, which includes his monumental sculpture of The Ship located in front of its entrance.
"

"Adeel Uz Zafar,http://www.lawrieshabibi.com/artists/49-adeel-uz-zafar/overview/</Address>
Adeel uz Zafar is known for his unique and meticulous scratching technique. His early practice involved engraving exposed photographic sheets with a paper cutter which was the base of his empirical observation and the development of his technique. Today Zafar works in minute detail on a large scale of black plastic vinyl sheets featuring gauzed stuffed animal toys completely alien to traditional <Origin>Pakistani</Origin> society. Zafar&apos;s work is both terrifying and amusing. His subject matters wrapped in bandages evoke childhood anxiety, turning comforting objects into monstrous figures. He gives his work a sinister feel by bandaging his objects and hiding them from view hinting to the loss of innocence and to the disintegration of the socio-political framework in <Location>Pakistan</Location> and to the pain that results.
Adeel uz Zafar was born in <Location>Karachi</Location>, <Location>Pakistan</Location> in <Date>1975</Date>. He completed his BFA from the <Organization>National College</Organization> (<Organization>NCA</Organization>) <Location>Lahore</Location>, graduating in <Date>1988</Date> and in <Date>2008</Date> joined <Organization>Indus Valley School</Organization> of Art. Zafar has taken part in a number of group exhibitions in <Location>Pakistan</Location> and in <Date>2010</Date> he exhibited at Fost Gallery in <Location>Singapore</Location> and Slick Art Fair, <Location>Paris</Location>. In <Date>2012</Date>, Zafar showed at Pulse Art Fair, <Location>NY</Location> and took part in a group exhibition titled Stop, Play, Pause, Repeat at <Organization>Lawrie Shabibi</Organization>. Most recently, the artist has been invited by the Parramatta Artist Studios in collaboration with <Organization>Cicada Press</Organization> (COFA, UNSW) for an international print making residency from <Date>15 April</Date> - <Date>17 May 2013</Date>.
"

"Adel Abdessemed,http://nadour.org/artists/adel-abdessemed/</Address>
Since the end of the ‘nineties, Adel Abdessemed has tackled the “problem areas” of our multicultural and globalised world with great intelligence. He confronts politics in a very personal way in order to highlight questions of morality and identity, both in the West and in the Muslim world.
His work, which includes installations, videos, photography, sculpture, drawings and book-work, is always visually effective without being at all literal. A blend of references to everyday situations with literary, mythological and philosophical allusions and symbols, his art holds for him the power to transform society in the sense that it in fact opposes a resistance to the conventional or the norm.
Of Kabyle descent, Adel Abdessemed was born in <Date>1971</Date> in <Location>Constantine</Location>, <Location>Algeria</Location>. He studied Fine <Organization>Art</Organization> at <Location>Batna</Location> and then in <Location>Algiers</Location>. Forced into exile in <Date>1994</Date> by mounting Islamist violence, he trained at the <Organization>College of Fine Art</Organization> in <Location>Lyon</Location>. In <Date>2001</Date>, he took part in the International Studio Programme at the <Organization>PS</Organization>1 <Organization>Contemporary Art Centre</Organization> in <Location>New York</Location>.
Many museums and modern art centres all over the world have devoted solo exhibitions to the artist: MAMCO in <Location>Geneva</Location>, the Magasin de <Location>Grenoble</Location>, the Kunstverein in <Location>Heidelberg</Location>, the <Organization>Institute of Art</Organization> in <Location>San Francisco</Location> as well as the <Organization>Parasol Unit Foundation</Organization> for <Organization>Contemporary</Organization> <Organization>Art</Organization> in <Location>London</Location>. From <Date>2001</Date> Abdessemed has also contributed to a number of biennials and triennials, which includes those in <Location>Yokohama</Location>, <Location>Tirana</Location>, <Location>Venice</Location>, <Location>Istanbul</Location>, <Location>Lyon</Location>, <Location>Havana</Location> and <Location>Sydney</Location>.
"

"Adel Abidin,http://www.lawrieshabibi.com/artists/71-adel-abidin/overview/</Address>
Abidin is a visual artist whose projects, whilst focused on global social, political, and cultural issues, traverse a complex landscape of identity, memory, exile, violence and war. Taking specific actions or objects out of their initial context he turns them on their head, creating ironic, darkly humorous and often absurdist responses, exploring issues such as cultural alienation and distorted realities. His video and sculptural installations often reference pop culture, racial stereotypes and traditional icons, designing tense situations of confrontation and dialogue that truly engage the viewer.
 In <Date>March 2013</Date> <Organization>Lawrie Shabibi</Organization> hosted the critically acclaimed solo exhibition &apos;Symphony&apos; curated by Basak Senova, which included the ambitious sculpture Al Warqaa commissioned by the <Organization>Barjeel Art Foundation</Organization>. The same month he held a solo exhibition &apos;Blueprint&apos; at <Organization>Maraya Arts Centre</Organization>, curated by Sara Raza. In <Date>2011</Date> he was part of <Organization>Sharjah Biennial</Organization> 10 and his video installation Three Love Songs was a highlight of the inaugural exhibition at <Organization>Mathaf Arab Museum of Arab Art</Organization>, <Location>Doha</Location>, &apos;Told/Untold/Retold&apos; curated by Sam Bardouil and Till Fellrath.  
Adel Abidin (b. <Location>Baghdad</Location>, <Date>1973</Date>) received a bachelor&apos;s degree in Painting from the <Organization>Academy of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Baghdad</Location> in <Date>2000</Date> and a Master&apos;s degree in <Organization>Media and New Media</Organization> <Organization>Art</Organization> from the <Organization>Academy of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Helsinki</Location>, <Location>Finland</Location> in <Date>2005</Date> where he continues to live and work.
Abidin has exhibited in numerous group and solo exhibitions, in <Date>2014</Date>: &apos;Between Us, Video <Organization>Art</Organization> from the <Location>Middle East</Location> and <Location>North Africa</Location> in a Global World&apos;, <Organization>Etopia Center</Organization> for <Organization>Art and Technology</Organization>, <Location>Zaragoza</Location>; &apos;Cover-up!&apos;, Al Sultan <Organization>Gallery</Organization>, <Location>Kuwait</Location>; &apos;Life is Short, Let&apos;s Have an Affair&apos;, Muu <Organization>Gallery</Organization>, <Location>Helsinki</Location>; &apos;Simple past, perfect futures&apos;, Le CENQUATRE-<Location>PARIS</Location>, <Location>Paris</Location>; &apos;Music Palace&apos;, <Organization>Boghossian Foundation</Organization>, Villa Empain, <Location>Brussels</Location>;  &apos;Shifting Identities&apos;, MACRO, <Location>Rome</Location>; &apos;Collective Reaction&apos;, <Organization>Station Museum</Organization>, <Location>Houston</Location>; &apos;<Organization>Arab</Organization> Contemporary&apos;, <Organization>Louisiana Museum of Modern Art</Organization>, Humlebaek; &apos;Here and Elswhere&apos;, <Organization>New Museum</Organization>, <Location>New York</Location>; &apos;Songs of Loss and Songs of Love&apos;, <Organization>Gwangiu Museum of Art</Organization>, <Location>South Korea</Location>; &apos;Late Modern and Contemporary <Organization>Art</Organization>&apos;, <Organization>National Gallery of Victoria</Organization>, <Location>Melbourne</Location>. Previously he has taken part in The <Organization>Helsinki KIASMA Museum of Contemporary Art</Organization>, The <Organization>DA</Organization>2 Domus Atrium <Date>2002</Date> <Organization>Centre of Contemporary Art</Organization> (Salamanca), Location One <Organization>Gallery</Organization> in <Location>New York City</Location>, <Organization>Arab</Organization> Express, <Organization>Mori Art Museum</Organization>, <Location>Tokyo</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>), the 17th <Organization>Sydney Biennale</Organization>, Aksanat (İstanbul), &apos; I Love to Love&apos;, Forum <Location>Box</Location> <Organization>Gallery</Organization>, <Location>Helsinki</Location>; the <Organization>Biennale</Organization> of Contemporary <Organization>Art</Organization> of <Location>Bosnia</Location>; <Organization>Hauser &amp; Wirth Gallery</Organization>, <Location>London</Location>; <Organization>Singapore Art Museum</Organization>; <Organization>Museum of Anthropology</Organization>, <Location>Vancouver</Location>; MOCCA, <Location>Toronto</Location>; Mead Gallery, <Location>UK</Location>; Espace at Louis Vuitton, <Location>Paris</Location>; <Organization>MAC-VAL Museum</Organization>, <Location>Paris</Location>; the 10th <Organization>Sharjah Biennial</Organization> and 52nd <Organization>Venice Biennale</Organization>, where he represented <Location>Finland</Location> and the <Origin>Iraqi</Origin> Pavilion at the 54th <Organization>Venice Biennale</Organization>; held solo shows at L&apos;<Organization>Institut du Monde Arabe</Organization>, <Location>Paris</Location>; Kunsthalle Winterthur, <Location>Switzerland</Location>; Darat al-Funun; <Location>Amman</Location> and Wharf: <Organization>Centre d&apos;Art Contemporain</Organization> de Basse, <Location>Normandy</Location>. 
His works are in the collections of public institutions and major private collections  including the <Organization>National Gallery of Victoria</Organization>, <Location>Melbourne</Location>, <Location>Australia</Location>; <Organization>Sharjah Art Foundation</Organization>, <Location>Sharjah</Location>, <Location>UAE</Location>; <Organization>Mathaf</Organization>: <Organization>Arab Museum of Modern Art</Organization>, <Location>Doha</Location>, <Location>Qatar</Location>; Kiasma, <Location>Helsinki</Location>, <Location>Finland</Location>; Espoo <Organization>Museum of Modern Art</Organization> (EMMA), <Location>Helsinki</Location>, <Location>Finland</Location>; <Organization>Mori Art Museum</Organization>, <Location>Tokyo</Location>, <Location>Japan</Location>; Nadour Collection and Kamel Lazaar Collection. 
In <Date>2012</Date> Abidin received a Five Years Grant from The <Organization>Art Council of Finland</Organization> and was a nominee for the Ars Fennica Prize in <Date>2011</Date>."

"Adham Wanly,http://www.encyclopedia.mathaf.org/en/bios/Pages/Adham-Wanly.aspx</Address>
Ibrahim Adham Wanly was born in <Date>1908</Date> in the neighborhood of <Date>Muharram</Date> Bey in <Location>Alexandria</Location>. His father, Ismaïl Bey Mohammed Wanly was of <Origin>Turkish</Origin> origin and his mother, Ismat Hanem al-Daghistani, was from Caucasia. <Organization>Adham</Organization> grew up, with his four sisters and his elder brother Seif in an aristocratic intellectual francophone environment and was educated by private tutors in the family palace of Urfan <Organization>Pacha</Organization>. <Organization>Adham</Organization> worked as the director of the book warehouse at the <Organization>Education Authority</Organization> in <Location>Alexandria</Location>.
Wanly first studied oil painting with his brother, Seif, in the studio of the <Origin>Italian</Origin> painter Arturo Zanieri (<Date>1870 - 1955</Date>) who had also been the teacher of Alexandrian painter <Organization>Mahmoud</Organization> Saïd (<Date>1897 - 1964</Date>). In 1929, the <Origin>Italian</Origin> painter, Ottorino Bicchi (<Date>1878 - 1949</Date>), educated at the Academy in <Location>Florence</Location>, opened a studio in <Location>Alexandria</Location> and the Wanly brothers were among his first students. When Bicchi closed his studio and returned to <Location>Italy</Location> before the Second World War, the Wanly brothers together with their friends, the painter Ahmad Fahmi and the filmmaker Mohammed Bayoumi, opened their own studio in <Location>Alexandria</Location> in <Date>1935</Date>.
During the 1950&apos;s, <Organization>Adham</Organization> and his brother traveled to many European countries including <Location>France</Location>, <Location>Italy</Location> and <Location>Spain</Location>, where they sketched and painted numerous landscapes, as well as ballet, opera and theater performances. In 1957, the Wanly brothers were appointed as professors at the <Organization>Faculty of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Alexandria</Location> founded the same year by the sculptor Ahmad Osman (<Date>1907 - 1970</Date>). Two years later, they were appointed by the <Organization>Ministry of Culture</Organization> to participate in recording the Nubian architectural heritage in <Location>Aswan</Location> before the area was due to be flooded by the construction of the High Dam . During that mission, along with many artists and professors of their generation, they produced numerous paintings and sketches of the Nubian vernacular villages and ancient temples. Adham Wanly died in <Date>1959</Date> at the age of fifty-one in al-Moassat hospital in <Location>Alexandria</Location>. After his death, the street next to his studio in <Location>Alexandria</Location> was named after him.
Adham Wanly, like his brother Seif, was a prolific artist. His early works are influenced by his <Origin>Italian</Origin> teacher, Ottorino Bicchi, who was close to the <Origin>Italian</Origin> macchiaioli, a group influenced by the <Origin>French</Origin> impressionist movement and the École de Barbizon. Bicchi introduced the Wanly brothers to outdoor painting and capturing the light, colors and shades of nature. <Organization>Adham</Organization> was later influenced by modern pictorial trends, such as cubism and fauvism. Together with his brother, he developed a passion for performance arts, such as circus, ballet and theater and captured the vibrant and dynamic movements of the performers on stage.
<Organization>Adham</Organization> also painted numerous landscapes of Alexandria, as well as views of <Location>Cairo</Location> and many European cities. With his brother Seif, he participated regularly in the Salons in <Location>Alexandria</Location> and <Location>Cairo</Location>, as well as in the Alexandria Biennale. In addition to being a painter, he was also a talented caricaturist and during the 1930&apos;s, he regularly published his satirical drawings in <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> newspapers and reviews, such al Ruz al-Yusuf. His works can be seen at the Seif and <Organization>Adham Wanly Museum</Organization> hosted in the villa of the <Organization>Mahmoud Saïd Museum</Organization> in <Location>Alexandria</Location>, the <Organization>Museum of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Alexandria</Location>, the <Organization>Museum of <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> Modern</Organization> Art in <Location>Cairo</Location>, the Mathaf: <Organization>Arab Museum of Modern Art</Organization> in <Location>Doha</Location>, as well as in numerous private collections around the world."

"Adila Laidi-Hanieh,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/l/laidi-hanieh-adila</Address>
Adila Laidi-Hanieh edited in <Date>2008</Date> the book <Location>Palestine</Location>: We Lack for Nothing Here (<Location>Palestine</Location>: Rien ne nous Manque ici, Cercle d’Art, <Location>Paris</Location>), a cultural review of contemporary <Location>Palestine</Location>, which commissioned texts and art work from confirmed and emerging artists, critics, novelists, poets, and visual artists from <Location>Palestine</Location> and elsewhere. <Date>From 1996 to 2005</Date>, she ran the <Organization>Khalil Sakakini Cultural Center</Organization> in Ramallah where she curated the <Date>2001</Date> memorial exhibition 100 Shaheed-100 Lives. She taught Palestinian contemporary art and modern Arab intellectual history at <Organization>Birzeit University</Organization>, and is currently a cultural studies PhD candidate at <Organization>George Mason University</Organization>.
<Date>March 2009</Date>
"

"Ahaad Alamoudi,http://edgeofarabia.com/artists/ahaad-alamoudi</Address>
Born in <Location>Jeddah</Location> in <Date>1991</Date>, Ahaad’s love for art was evident from a young age; her mother an artist and art teacher, Ahaad was always surrounded by artworks and art materials. She moved to <Location>England</Location> and that broadened her view and appreciation for art, and the world. She loves how people could express themselves with different media and affect people’s mindsets and lives. This is what motivated her to continue perusing art when she returned to <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location>. Ahaad is currently studying Visual Communication at <Organization>Dar Al Hekma</Organization>, hoping to continue studying art and expressing herself through it."

"Ahmad Amin Nazar,http://ivde.net/artists/ahmad_amin_nazar_1/biography</Address>
Amin Nazar (b. 1955, <Location>Iran</Location>) studied fine art in <Location>Tehran</Location>, and after eight years in <Location>Cologne</Location>, <Location>Germany</Location>, where he joined the <Organization>Society of Painters</Organization> of <Location>Cologne</Location> and was widely exposed to Western art, returned to <Location>Iran</Location>. Upon his return, he began predominantly working in etching, exploring relationships between miniaturist traditions and <Origin>Iranian</Origin> literature, and went on to develop a masterful draughtmanship. His work manifests the discordance between traditions, both from <Location>Iran</Location> and the West, and modernity. Persian epics, legendary figures, social leaders and macho wrestlers are transformed into disturbed, witty, violent and sensual studies, ink drawings and acrylic masterpieces. The artist has taught drawing to younger generations of <Origin>Iranian</Origin> artists at <Organization>Tehran University</Organization> as well as privately for many years.
Amin Nazar belongs to a lost generation of <Origin>Iranian</Origin> artists who, due to historical circumstances, were drowned out in the midst of ideological, political, cultural and violent turmoil. As a result, he became profoundly reclusive, seeking refuge and absolute release in his studio, and in his raw, instinctive works.
Despite shying away from the public eye, Amin Nazar’s works are surfacing internationally, most recently with the acquisition of the <Organization>British Museum</Organization> of two works on paper of wrestlers, one of which was exhibited as part of the ‘Fair Play: heroes, athletes and princes in Islamic art’ exhibition, <Date>2012</Date>."

"Ahmad Ghossein,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/g/ghossein-ahmad</Address>
Ahmad Ghossein is a filmmaker. He who won the Best Director Prize at the <Organization>Beirut International</Organization> Film Festival (<Date>2004</Date>) for his short film Operation N… after having graduated with a degree in Theatre Arts from the <Organization>Lebanese University</Organization>. He has since directed several documentaries and video works including 210m (<Date>2007</Date>) produced by Ashkal Alwan, Faces Applauding Alone (<Date>2008</Date>), what does not resemble me looks exactly like me with Ghassan Salhab and Mohamad Soueid (<Date>2009</Date>) and An Arab Comes to Town (<Date>2008</Date>), a documentary filmed in <Location>Denmark</Location> produced by DR2. Ahmad also is a performer and is one of the founders of Maqamat Dance Theatre. He is currently preparing his first feature film.
"

"Ahmad Konash,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-ahmadkonash.html</Address>
Ahmad Konash (Al-Khobar, <Date>1982</Date>)is a gaphic designer, calligrapher, painter and photographer who has been a director in an advertising firm, but wrote he was &quot;kinda starting to &apos;dis-like&apos; advertising .. i miss designing for designing.&quot; He is a user of the <Organization>Khatt Foundation</Organization> network for Arab typography and some of his graphic designs were published in Arabesque (<Location>Berlin</Location>, <Date>2007</Date>). He has a website where his portfolio may be seen including his &apos;first paintings ever.&apos; In the fall of <Date>2008</Date> he was living in <Location>Vancouver</Location> (<Location>Canada</Location>) studying for a MA in media arts. He has since been producing video&apos;s which he shows on Youtube. They are about a.o. his mother and artist father and a <Location>Vancouver</Location> sword dance.
"

"Ahmad Morshedloo,http://nadour.org/artists/ahmad-morshedloo/</Address>
Ahmad Morshedloo carefully composes large-scale oil paintings as well as pen or charcoal drawings woven with meticulous lines and hatchings. He finds his inspiration in observing daily and ordinary scenes around him. His characters are always caught at times of inaction, immobility, reflection or even sleep. The impression of familiarity is then being replaced by strangeness and realism, which serve the purposes of introspection and dramaturgy.
Born in <Date>1973</Date> in Mashhad, in the <Location>North-East</Location> of <Location>Iran</Location>, Ahmad Morshedloo studied painting in <Location>Teheran</Location>, at the <Organization>Azad University</Organization> then at the <Organization>University of Art</Organization>, from which he graduated in <Date>2001</Date>. He now lives and works in <Location>Teheran</Location> and is a member of the <Origin>Iranian</Origin> Painters Organisation (S.I.P.) as well as the 30+ Group.
His work has been extensively shown in <Location>Iran</Location> since end <Date>the 90s</Date>, and is now exhibited abroad as part of group shows in museums, like the <Organization>Tokyo Metropolitan Museum</Organization>, the <Location>Berlin</Location> Pergamon museum, as well as galleries, in <Location>Milan</Location>, <Location>Beijing</Location>, <Location>London</Location> and <Location>New York</Location>. Morshedloo has particularly taken part in the <Date>2009</Date> exhibitions “Unveiled: New <Organization>Art</Organization> from the <Location>Middle East</Location>” organized in <Location>London</Location> by the Saatchi Gallery and “<Location>Iran</Location> Inside Out” at the <Organization>Chelsea Art Museum</Organization> in <Location>New York</Location>.
"

"Ahmad Osman,http://www.encyclopedia.mathaf.org/en/bios/Pages/Ahmad-Osman.aspx</Address>
Ahmad Osman was born in the small village of <Location>Eneiba</Location> near <Location>Aswan</Location> in Nubia. He studied at the <Organization>School of Decorative Arts</Organization> in <Location>Cairo</Location> under the <Origin>English</Origin> painter and decorator William Arnold Stewart (<Date>1882 - 1953</Date>). After graduating in <Date>1927</Date>, he worked with the Mission of the <Organization>University of Pennsylvania</Organization> as the registrar for the archaeological excavations in <Location>Palestine</Location>. In 1928, he received a scholarship to study in <Location>Rome</Location>, where he first took classes at the Scuola Libera del Disegno del Nudo before entering the sculpture section of the <Organization>Royal Academy</Organization> of Fine <Organization>Arts</Organization>. After receiving his diploma in <Date>1932</Date>, he traveled to <Location>Florence</Location> to specialize in decorative sculpture at the Regio Instituto d&apos;Arte. The following year, he returned to <Location>Egypt</Location> where he was appointed professor of sculpture at the <Organization>School of Applied Arts</Organization> in Giza (former School of Decorative <Organization>Arts</Organization>). At that time, the School was directed by the artist Mohammed Hassan (<Date>1892 - 1961</Date>).
In 1937, Osman was named director of the sculpture section of the <Organization>School of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Cairo</Location>. The same year, he participated in the decoration of the <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> Pavilion at the Exposition Internationale des Arts et Techniques appliqués à la Vie moderne in <Location>Paris</Location>, headed by the <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> politician and collector Mohammed Mahmoud Khalil (<Date>1877 - 1953</Date>). In 1938 he exhibited at the fifteenth <Organization>Venice Biennale</Organization> together with artists Mohammed Naghi (<Date>1888 - 1956</Date>) and Mahmoud Saïd (<Date>1897 - 1964</Date>), where <Location>Egypt</Location> was represented for the first time. Osman left his position at the <Organization>School of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Cairo</Location> in <Date>1957</Date> to establish the <Organization>Faculty of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Alexandria</Location> of which he became the first director.
Besides his occupations as an artist and teacher, he was involved in the safeguarding of the <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> cultural heritage. In 1954, he participated in the relocation of the colossal statue of Ramses II from Mit Rahina (<Location>Memphis</Location>) to Bab al-Hadid square in front of <Location>Cairo</Location> railway station. He also participated in Unesco&apos;s Nubian campaign from 1959, by developing techniques for cutting and reassembling the stone blocks of the <Location>Temple</Location> of Abu Simbel.
Ahmad Osman was one of the most prominent <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> sculptors of his generation. While his early works employ characteristics of <Origin>Italian</Origin> classicism, towards the end of the 1930&apos;s he started sculpting a series of bronzes representing busts of <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> peasant women. These sculptures are characterized by their realism in depicting the features of the peasants and daily rural activities. They embody the simplicity and joyfulness of rural life, which he often expressed through a smiling <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> peasant. Osman also specialized in ornamental sculptures and was commissioned to decorate several public buildings. In 1936, together with his colleague, the sculptor Mansour Farag, he created the reliefs to decorate the entrance gate of the Zoological <Location>Garden</Location> in Giza designed by architect Mustafa Fahmi (<Date>1886 - 1972</Date>). In 1947, he sculpted the bronze reliefs decorating the pedestal of the monument to commemorate Ibrahim Pasha on the <Organization>Opera</Organization> square in <Location>Cairo</Location>, which was created by the <Origin>French</Origin> sculptor Charles Cordier (<Date>1829 - 1905</Date>).
Under Gamal Abdel Nasser, Osman was commissioned to sculpt the exterior façades of the <Organization>Officers Club</Organization> in Zamalek and the <Organization>Armed Forces Club</Organization> in Heliopolis, as well as the monumental stylized bronze eagle above the entrance of the <Location>Cairo</Location> Tower in <Date>1961</Date>. Osman was also a talented painter and produced a series of feminine and masculine nudes with charcoal, as well as several portraits, genres he developed while studying at the Scuola Libera del Disegno del Nudo. In his drawings, Osman reflects his background as a sculptor, by applying clear lines and shades on sculptural volumes. His works can be found in private collections, the <Organization>Museum of <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> Modern</Organization> Art in <Location>Cairo</Location>, the <Organization>Agriculture Museum</Organization> in <Location>Cairo</Location>, the <Organization>Museum of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Alexandria</Location> and the Mathaf: <Organization>Arab Museum of Modern Art</Organization> in <Location>Doha</Location>."

"Ahmed Alsoudani,http://edgeofarabia.com/artists/ahmed-alsoudani</Address>
Born in <Location>Baghdad</Location>, <Location>Iraq</Location> in <Date>1975</Date>, Ahmed Alsoudani graduated from the <Organization>Yale School of Art</Organization> in <Date>2008</Date> and currently lives and works in <Location>New York</Location>. His work has been included in museum exhibitions at the <Organization>Minneapolis Institute of Art</Organization> (<Date>2011</Date>), The <Organization>Arab Museum of Modern Art</Organization> in <Location>Doha</Location>, <Location>Qatar</Location> (<Date>2011</Date>) and the Saatchi Gallery’s Unveiled: New <Organization>Art</Organization> from the <Location>Middle East</Location> (<Date>2009</Date>). A monograph of his work has recently been published by Hatje Cantz (<Date>2009</Date>) and he has been profiled in Der Spiegel, <Organization>Art</Organization> + <Organization>Auction</Organization> and <Organization>Canvas Magazine</Organization>. His work has been critically reviewed in The <Date>Sunday</Date> <Organization>Times</Organization> and <Organization>The Independent</Organization>, Artnet and other publications. Alsoudani’s work is held in the collections of the <Organization>Columbus Museum of Art</Organization>, the <Organization>Pinault Foundation</Organization> collection, the <Organization>Qatar Museum</Organization> and private collections around the world. His work will be featured in the <Location>Iraq</Location> Pavilion at the <Date>2011</Date> 54th <Organization>Venice Biennale</Organization> and also shown in the <Organization>Pinault Foundation</Organization> at <Organization>Palazzo Grassi</Organization>. Ahmed Alsoudani is represented by Haunch of Venison Gallery, <Location>London</Location>."

"Ahmed Cherkaoui,http://www.encyclopedia.mathaf.org/en/bios/Pages/Ahmed-Cherkaoui.aspx</Address>
Ahmed Cherkaoui was one of the leading modernist painters of <Origin>Moroccan</Origin> art in the period after the country gained its independence in <Date>1956</Date>. Born in a small town, Boujad, located in the Chaouia plain, Cherkaoui descended, from his father&apos;s side, from &quot;a famous family of mystics&quot; called the &quot;Sufi brotherhood of the Cherkaoua.&quot; The brotherhood was founded in <Date>1566</Date> during the reign of the Saadian sultans. His mother was of Amazighi origin, belonging to the Zayanes tribe from the Middle Atlas. The tribe was known for women&apos;s traditionally made handcrafts and wool weaving.
Cherkaoui studied graphics at the École des Metiers d&apos;Art de <Location>Paris</Location> <Date>from 1956 to 1959</Date>, and continued his studies at the Aujame Atelier at the École Nationale Supérieure des Beaux-<Organization>Arts</Organization> de <Location>Paris</Location> for one year. In 1961, during the political and cultural thaw following the death of Stalin, Cherkaoui moved to <Location>Warsaw</Location> where he studied at the <Organization>Academy of Fine Arts</Organization>. Later Cherkaoui returned to <Location>Paris</Location>, where he won a research grant from <Organization>UNESCO</Organization> to study signs and symbols in Amazighi art and Arab-Islamic calligraphy. During the early sixties, he held his first one-man show at the Atelier de Lucienne Thalheimer in <Location>Paris</Location> where he lived and worked.
Cherkaoui created large-scale abstract and symbolic canvases which negotiated an amalgam of references, ranging from Amazighi art, talismanic symbols to Roger Bissière, Paul Klee and Surrealism. The surface of these canvases are covered with burlap onto which Cherkaoui painted black-striped symbols crafted within an oval structure and laid at intervals with bright colors. The Maghreb, &quot;the place of the setting sun,&quot; and more specifically the Amazighi tradition of the bare geometric sign are all intrinsic to the artist. Since his young age, his fascination with signs stemmed from his curiosity about the shapes and meaning of his mother&apos;s tattoos. Later on, he embraced the teachings and philosophy of Paul Klee, who wrote, &quot;Man is not a completed product…We must…be open-minded…approach life like a child…of creation, of the creator&apos;s,&quot; and made them a guiding rule of his own spirit.
The desire to paint for Ahmed Cherkaoui is partially attributed to his interest in calligraphy and the motifs of popular talismans, and partly to his exposure to 20th century <Location>Western Modern</Location> art. Consequently, Cherkaoui&apos;s works reveal a concrete manifestation of a tangible interplay between tradition and modernity, negotiating both the aesthetic and abstract nature of signs and symbols which govern both Islamic art and new innovative techniques. However, Cherkaoui&apos;s resort to signs consists of far more than merely presenting their decorative function. He used a system of geometric signs and ciphers, including triangles, circles, lozenges, dots and broken and curved lines. These signs voice stories about a particular social system that are open to interpretation. As such, his creative artwork presented intriguing and visually complex forms which highlight his profound interest in national heritage.
In 1964, Cherkaoui held an exhibition at Jeanne Castel&apos;s Gallery in <Location>Paris</Location>, and other exhibitions in <Location>Rabat</Location>, <Location>Tangier</Location> and <Location>Casablanca</Location> in <Location>Morocco</Location>, where he explored and developed a personal modern style, he expressed in crude jute collages. After his collages, he went through a phase that he referred to as &quot;tachiste&quot; or formlessness, where he emphasized the value of color.
During the early sixties, his artwork depicted various forms drawn from outlines of tattoos, pottery, jewelry, weaving and motifs on handicraft ware, combining both bright and earth colors to highlight the cultural characteristics of his country of origin (al-Maghreb—&quot;sunset in the sea&quot;). While dark colors dominated his paintings before 1965, his colors afterwards became lighter and more lustrous with greater awareness of the use of space and additional media such as fiber, gouache and watercolor.
Cherkaoui&apos;s works received recognition early on as he won the bronze medal at the 10th &quot;Salon Interministériel&quot; in <Date>1962</Date> and took part regularly in the Salon de Mai in <Location>Paris</Location>. He participated in many solo exhibitions including his one-man show at the Ursula Girardon&apos;s Gallery in <Date>1962</Date> in <Location>Paris</Location>; and numerous collective exhibitions, including &quot;20 Peintres étrangers&quot; in the Parisian Musée de l&apos;Art Moderne in <Date>1963</Date>.
Cherkaoui taught drawing classes at the <Organization>Technical College</Organization> in <Location>Beaumont</Location>-sur-Oise. He was generally associated with a small group of painters in <Location>Casablanca</Location> including Houssein Tallal and Andre Elbaz although he was never part of the <Organization>Casablanca School</Organization>. Cherkaoui traveled frequently between <Location>Europe</Location> and <Location>North Africa</Location>, and died suddenly due to complications from an appendectomy in <Date>1967</Date> after coming back to <Location>Casablanca</Location>, <Location>Morocco</Location>.
After his death, his work was represented in a series of retrospective shows entitled Hommage à Cherkaoui organized at the Biennale de <Location>Paris</Location> and also at the Salon of Sacred Art in <Location>Paris</Location>; followed by the Biennale Exhibit of <Location>New Delhi</Location> in <Date>1968</Date> in <Location>India</Location>. His works were also featured at the interférences Poetes-Peintres group show at the Daniel Templon Gallery, one of Cherkaoui&apos;s watercolor works accompanying the poem &apos;talisman&apos; written by Jean Guichard Meili in <Location>Paris</Location> in <Date>1969</Date>.
"

"Ahmed El Attar
Theatre director,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/a/attar-ahmed-el</Address>
Ahmed El Attar is an <Origin>Egyptian</Origin> independent theatre director, translator and playwright. He is founder and artistic director of the <Organization>Temple Independent Theatre Company</Organization> and of Orient Productions for film and theatre. 
El Attar is also the founder and general manager of the <Organization>Studio Emad Eddin Foundation</Organization> that provides rehearsal, residencies and training space to performing artists in <Location>Cairo</Location>.
His works, which address socially relevant themes, have been performed to public and critical acclaim throughout the Arab world and the West. He presented two performances during the 9th <Organization>Sharjah Biennial</Organization>: On the importance of being an Arab (<Date>2009</Date>) and The Committee (<Date>1998</Date>).
El Attar&apos;s most recent work Hassan X 2 and the Magic Well (<Date>2009</Date>) is a major production for children that explores issues of class discrimination and the global water crisis. Other work includes F**K Darwin, or How I’ve Learned to Love Socialism (<Date>2007</Date>) which won the best actor award at the <Organization>Cairo International</Organization> Experimental Theatre Festival (<Date>2007</Date>), Othello, or Who’s Afraid of William Shakespeare (<Date>2006</Date>), Mother I want to be a Millionaire (<Date>2004</Date>) and Life is Beautiful or Waiting for My Uncle From <Location>America</Location> (<Date>2000</Date>).
Ahmed El Attar has a <Organization>BA</Organization> in Theatre from the <Organization><Origin>American</Origin> University</Organization> in <Location>Cairo</Location> and an MA in <Organization>Arts and Cultural Management</Organization> from <Location>Paris</Location> III Sorbonne Nouvelle and was recently a <Location>Chevening</Location> scholar on the Clore Leadership Programme (<Location>UK</Location>). He is a member of several international boards and advisory committees including Femec - Forum Euroméditerranéen des Cultures. In <Date>2005</Date> El Attar was chosen by the Arabic edition of <Organization>Newsweek</Organization> as one of 42 personalities influencing change in the Arab world.
<Date>October 2010</Date>
"

"Ahmed Felemban ,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-ahmedfelemban.html</Address>
Ahmed Felemban is a <Origin>Saudi</Origin> art teacher and artist who studied in <Location>Italy</Location> and has been responisble for organizing exhibitions in <Location>Jeddah</Location> in the <Organization><Origin>Italian</Origin> Cultural Centre</Organization> in co-operation with the <Origin><Organization>Italian</Organization></Origin> Consul General. Felemban went to <Location>Italy</Location> in <Date>1967</Date> and graduated from the <Organization>Rome Academy</Organization> in <Date>1971</Date>. 
In <Date>November 2007</Date> he organized an exhibition, under the patronage of <Location>Makkah</Location> governor prince Khalid Al-Faisal, featuring 6 <Origin>Saudi</Origin> graduates from <Origin>Italian</Origin> art schools: Dia Aziz Dia, Mohamed Al-Saquabi, Kamal Al-Muallim, Othman Al-Khuzaim, Mohamed Mansour Al-Aajam and Felemban himself.
In a first interview with Arab News Felemban about this exhibition he was quoted to have said something that seems to be expected of all <Origin>Saudi</Origin> artists: &quot;the techniques we acquired from <Location>Italy</Location> were merged to the <Origin>Saudi</Origin> spirit, its culture and heritage.&quot;
A week later in another interview he makes clear that such behaviour was because society was not ready to recieve them back from <Location>Italy</Location>. Out of necessity he became a teacher. He refers to the fact that the education minister at the time wanted to establish an art academy in <Location>Jeddah</Location> but was unable to do so. Felemban was then quoted:
&quot;Our <Origin>Saudi</Origin> art has no identity, we are still looking for an identity. <Origin>Saudi</Origin> art needs to be shaped by having a society or a school to supply the basics.&quot;
In <Date>May 2008</Date> Felemban again with the <Organization><Origin>Italian</Origin> consulate</Organization> organized an exhibition, but now for 5 women artists. (<Date>2009</Date>).
"

"Ahmed Foula
Graphic Designer,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/f/foula-ahmed</Address>
Ahmed Foula was born in <Location>Alexandria</Location>, <Location>Egypt</Location>, <Date>1979</Date>, and studied Architecture at the <Organization>Faculty of Fine Arts</Organization> in <Location>Alexandria</Location> University. For over 7 years, he practised as a freelance graphic designer and led branding and advertising campaigns for artistic and cultural spaces as well as exhibitions and events in <Location>Egypt</Location> and across the Arab World.
In <Date>2008</Date>, Foula curated a collective Graphic Art project titled Breaking Boredom which brought together six of <Location>Egypt</Location>’s most celebrated graphic designers. He was then co-curator of Roto, a project which explored the uses of the rotoscoping technique in the production of animated short films. For Past of the Coming Days he was commissioned to create a site specific design project in which he collaborated with other designers to produce work that could be viewed in various locations around <Location>Sharjah</Location>. His recent work has been created from a process of integrating previous architectural and graphical experiences into novel artistic experiments.
Currently lives and works in <Location>Montreal</Location>, <Location>Canada</Location>.
<Date>November 2010</Date>
"

"Ahmed Mater,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/m/mater-ahmed</Address>
b.<Date>1979</Date> in <Location>Tabuk</Location>, <Origin>Saudi</Origin> ArabiaLives and works in <Location>Abha</Location>, <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location>
 
Ahmed Mater grew up in <Location>Abha</Location>, the capital of Aseer (in the south of <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location>) far from the urban centres of <Location>Saudi Arabia</Location>. He remains rooted to its identity and leads a young artistic collective called Ibn Aseer (Son of Aseer). Mater studied medicine and has become an integral part of the history of Abha’s <Organization>Miftaha Arts Village</Organization>. Mater also co-founded <Organization>Edge of Arabia</Organization> in <Date>2008</Date>.
His recent work presents an unofficial history of <Origin>Saudi</Origin> sociopolitical life. It is concerned with the representation of traumatic events of collective historical dimensions, and the ways in which films, video, image, performance and text can document physical and psychological violence.
Mater’s work has been widely exhibited internationally including The <Organization>Mori Museum of Art</Organization>, <Location>Tokyo</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>), The <Organization>Nelson-Atkins Museum of Art</Organization>, <Location>Kansas City</Location> (<Date>2013</Date>), <Organization>Sharjah Biennial</Organization> 11, <Location>Sharjah</Location> (<Date>2013</Date>), Rijksmuseum Volkenkunde, <Organization>Leiden Museum of Ethnology</Organization> (<Date>2013</Date>), Home Works 6 at Ashkal Alwan in <Location>Beirut</Location> (<Date>2013</Date>), and Galleria Continua’s Le <Location>Moulin</Location>, <Location>Paris</Location> (<Date>2013</Date>).
He was invited to participate in a number of panels and talks: The Louvre (<Date>2010</Date>), <Location>Berlin</Location> Akademie der Kunste (<Date>2010</Date>), The Armory Show <Location>New York</Location> (<Date>2011</Date>), <Organization>Art</Organization> Basel <Location>Miami</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>), <Organization>Leiden Museum Amsterdam</Organization> (<Date>2013</Date>).
His work is in the collection of the <Organization>British Museum (London)</Organization>, <Organization>Victoria &amp; Albert Museum (London)</Organization>, <Organization>Los Angeles County Museum of Art (Los Angeles)</Organization>, The <Organization>Museum of Islamic Art (Doha)</Organization> and <Organization>Centre Pompidou (Paris)</Organization>.
"

"Ahmed Tayseer Badrah,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-ahmedtayseerbadrah.html</Address>
Ahmed Tayseer Badrah (<Date>1988</Date>) is a graphic designer, photographer and video blogger of Palestinian birth who lives in <Location>Jeddah</Location> and has studied in <Location>Malaysia</Location>. He shows some of his photographs like Tomato Potatoe Onion, which was taken in old <Location>Jeddah</Location>, in a gallery on deviantART.
"

"Aisha Khalid,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/k/khalid-aisha</Address>
After receiving her BFA from the <Organization>National College of Arts</Organization> in <Location>Lahore</Location>, Khalid spent two years at the Rijksakademie in <Location>Amsterdam</Location> in <Date>2002</Date>. Her video and multi-media work combines multiple temporal, spatial, cultural, political and aesthetic references. Over the <Date>last decade</Date> she has had solo exhibitions in <Location>Pakistan</Location>, the <Location>US</Location>, <Location>India</Location> and the <Location>UK</Location> and has participated in numerous group shows including the <Date>2009</Date> <Organization>Venice Biennale</Organization>. She lives and works in <Location>Lahore</Location>.
"

"Akram Zaatari,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/z/zaatari-akram</Address>
Akram Zaatari co-founded the <Organization>Arab Image Foundation</Organization> in <Date>the 1990s</Date>. Zaatari’s work is deeply invested in researching photographic practices in the <Location>Middle East</Location>. His videos, publications and photographic installations look into technologies of image production and communication and the notions of surveillance, exploring the way different media apparatuses get employed in the service of power, resistance and memory. His videos include In this <Organization>House</Organization> (<Date>2005</Date>), This Day, (<Date>2003</Date>), Her + Him Van Leo (<Date>2001</Date>), All is Well on the Border (<Date>1997</Date>) and many more. His work has been shown at the <Organization>Tate Modern</Organization>, <Organization>French Cinemathèque</Organization>, the <Organization>Oberhausen Short Film Festival</Organization>, <Organization>Centre Georges Pompidou</Organization>, <Location>Paris</Location>, Haus der Kunst, <Location>Munich</Location>, the <Organization>Sfeir-Semler Gallery Beirut</Organization>/<Location>Hamburg</Location>, among others. He was part of the <Organization>Venice Biennale</Organization> (<Date>2007</Date>) and the <Organization>Gawangju</Organization>, <Location>Sydney</Location> and <Location>Sao</Location> Paolo biennials (<Date>2006</Date>). He lives and works in <Location>Beirut</Location>.
"

"Ala Ebtekar,http://www.thethirdline.com/artists/ala-ebtekar/biography/</Address>
Ala Ebtekar was born in <Location>Berkeley</Location> in <Date>1978</Date> and obtained a Bachelor of Fine Arts from <Organization>San Francisco Art Institute</Organization> in <Date>2002</Date> followed by a Masters of Fine Arts from <Organization>Stanford University</Organization> in <Date>2006</Date>. He is currently a visiting lecturer in the <Organization>Department of Art</Organization> &amp; <Organization>Art</Organization> History at <Organization>Stanford University</Organization>. Through a steady career that has incorporated sculpture, photography and installation, Ala has continually returned to his initial passion of drawing and painting. The artist’s practice is informed by history, Persian mythology, science and philosophy, which he juxtaposes with contemporary and pop-culture elements – the works eventually exhibiting a collision of the past and present in a deconstruction/reconstruction of time and space.
Ala’s work has been widely exhibited internationally. His solo shows include Parallax, Gallery Paule Anglim, <Location>San Francisco</Location>, <Location>USA</Location> (<Date>2014</Date>); Absent Arrival, Gallery Paule Anglim, <Location>San Francisco</Location>, <Location>USA</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>); Elsewhen, <Organization>The Third Line</Organization>, <Location>Dubai</Location>, <Location>UAE</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>); Indelible Whispers of <Organization>the Sun</Organization>, Charlie James Gallery, <Location>Los Angeles</Location>, <Location>USA</Location> (<Date>2010</Date>); Re-emergence, Gallery Paule Anglim, <Location>San Francisco</Location>, <Location>USA</Location> (<Date>2010</Date>); 1388, <Organization>The Third Line</Organization>, <Location>Dubai</Location> <Location>UAE</Location> (<Date>2009</Date>); Hampah, Charlie James Gallery, <Location>Los Angeles</Location>, <Location>USA</Location> (<Date>2009</Date>); Emergence, <Organization>Richmond Art Center</Organization>, <Location>Richmond</Location>, <Location>California</Location>, <Location>USA</Location> (<Date>2006</Date>).
His work has also been featured in numerous group exhibitions, including The Vastness is Bearable, <Organization>Museum of Contemporary Art</Organization>, <Location>Santa Barbara</Location>, <Location>California</Location>, CA (<Date>2013</Date>); The Beginning of Thinking is Geometric, <Organization>Maraya Art Centre</Organization>, <Location>Sharjah</Location>, <Location>UAE</Location> (<Date>2013</Date>); Migrating Identities, <Organization>Yerba Buena Centre</Organization> for the Arts, <Location>San Francisco</Location> Proximities//What Time Is It There?, <Organization>Asian Art Museum</Organization>, <Location>San Francisco</Location>, <Location>CA</Location>, <Location>USA</Location> (<Date>2013</Date>); Post-Pop, <Location>Mahe</Location> Mehr Gallery, <Location>Tehran</Location>, <Location>Iran</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>); <Organization>Art</Organization> World After <Date>1989</Date>, <Organization>Museum of Contemporary Art</Organization>, Lorenzstrasse, <Location>Germany</Location> (<Date>2012</Date>); The Global Contemporary: <Organization>Art</Organization> Worlds after <Date>1989</Date>, ZKM – <Organization>Museum of Contemporary Art</Organization>, Karlsruhe, <Location>Germany</Location> (<Date>2011</Date>); <Location>Iran</Location> Inside Out, <Organization>Chelsea Art Museum</Organization>, <Location>New York</Location>, <Location>USA</Location> (<Date>2009</Date>); SELSELEH/ZELZELEH: <Organization>Movers &amp; Shakers</Organization> in Contemporary <Origin>Iranian</Origin> <Organization>Art</Organization>, Leila Heller Gallery, <Location>New York</Location>, <Location>USA</Location> (<Date>2009</Date>) and One Way of Another: <Organization>Asian</Organization> <Origin>American</Origin> <Organization>Art</Organization> Now, <Organization>Asia Society Museum</Organization>, <Location>New York</Location>. He participated in Frieze <Location>London</Location> in <Date>2013</Date> and Frieze <Location>New York</Location> in <Date>2012</Date>.
Ala’s works are part of several notable public and private collections including the <Organization>Whitney Museum of <Origin>American</Origin> Art</Organization>, <Location>New York</Location>, <Location>USA</Location>; <Organization>Berkeley Art Museum</Organization>, CA, <Location>USA</Location>; <Organization>Deutsche Bank</Organization>, <Location>Frankfurt</Location>, <Location>Germany</Location>; de <Organization>Young Fine Arts Museum</Organization>, <Location>San Francisco</Location>, <Location>USA</Location>; and <Organization>Farjam Collection</Organization>, <Location>UAE</Location>.
Ala currently lives and works in <Location>California</Location>, <Location>USA</Location>."

"Alan Bishop,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/b/bishop-alan</Address>
As a founding member of the experimental music/performance group <Location>Sun City</Location> Girls, Alan Bishop has composed for, performed on and/or produced many critically acclaimed recordings over the <Date>past 30 years</Date> and is a highly influential elder of the <Origin>American</Origin> Underground music world. <Organization>His Abduction Records</Organization> label was founded in <Date>1993</Date> and is still operating <Date>today</Date> with 45 releases to date. He is also a music researcher, filmmaker, collage artist, writer and archivist incorporating areas as diverse as folk, jazz and improvisational music, manifesto text documents and travel journals, spoken word rants on conspiracy theory and various Middle Eastern and Asian cultural influences into his own processing laboratory. Besides continuing a solo career as Alvarius B., Alan’s current obsession is to expose great lost treasures of sound, ceremony and experiences from under-appreciated musical legacies across the world through Sublime Frequencies, the record label he has managed and operated as majority owner since <Date>2003</Date>.
"

"Alexandar Ugay,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/u/ugay-alexandar</Address>
Alexandar Ugay is a photographer and video artist. He was born in <Date>1978</Date> in Kyzilorda in <Location>Kazakhstan</Location> and lives and works in Almaty. Most recently, he took part in Promises of the Past at the <Organization>Centre Pompidou</Organization>, <Location>Paris</Location>.
"

"Ali Al-Ruzaiza,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-alialruzaiza.html</Address>
Ali Al-Ruzaiza (<Date>1947</Date>) is one of those rare artists who will paint even if there is no paint. He made it himself in the village where he was raised in the Al-Washim region and cut his own hair to make its brush. Don&apos;t ask when his work is finished. It never is. There is always more paint to be made. It is the creative impuls itself.
His art education was in schools in <Location>Riyadh</Location> when in his perception such education at the high end of society was better than in present times. His mind was further openend when from <Date>1974-1979</Date> he studied in <Location>Rome</Location>. Ruzaiza&apos;s work is however not <Origin>Italian</Origin>, but is inspired by traditional design from the <Location>Najd</Location> culture. 
His oilpaintings have ended up in the Al Mansouria collection and with several world leaders. The artist is much admired in <Location>Riyadh</Location>. His most important work is perhaps the house which he has been continuously building there. He is vocally supportive of the independent spirit of a new generation of young artists.
"

"Ali Al-Tokhais,http://www.greenboxmuseum.com/sa-alialtokhais.html</Address>
Ali Al-Tokhais (<Date>1956</Date>) is a sculptor by the incident of his birth in Al-Dawadmi. Al-Dawadmi, or &apos;The High of the <Location>Najd</Location>,&apos; is a hill top town, west of Riyadh, where it is said that a tradition of sculpture has continued over the ages after introduction in the 15th century. They have been farming the rock is what comes to mind, if rock is indeed what the <Location>Najd</Location> hills are made off. <Location>Rock</Location> is the artist&apos;s preferred medium on which he concentrates striving for absolute proficiency. The result of this, the rock which went through his hands, mind, heart and fingers has been on show to the public in the <Location>Middle East</Location> and other countries around the globe at frequent exhibitions since <Date>1985</Date>. A large selection of his works can be seen on his own website. And this website is worth visiting for another reason. Ali Al-Tokhais is a professor of sculpture and shows with pride pictures of his students with their work.Al-Tokhais has said that the Arabic alphabet is a silent influence in his work that by itself is abstract. But the abstraction is taken away again by contemplation while the rock is revealing its new form or perhaps as an afterthought. So the works of rock find themselves entrusted with titles which carry meaning. And sometimes, as is probabaly the case with Penetration, the rock is trusted with the nation itself. 
Source:,www.altokhaisart.comwww.arabnews.com24</Address> <Date>December</Date> 2005Carving out a Future for Sculpture by Razan Baker.&#169; All rights reserved.
"

"Ali Essafi,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/e/essafi-ali</Address>
Ali Essafi studied Psychology in <Location>France</Location>. His directorial debut titled General, Here We Come! (Général, nous voilà!, <Date>1997</Date>), a documentary about <Origin>Moroccan</Origin> veterans in the <Origin>French</Origin> army, was awarded the Special Jury Award at the <Location>Namur</Location> Film Festival. Essafi is one of <Location>Morocco</Location>’s most prolific and awarded documentary filmmakers. His films include The Silence of the Beet Fields (Le Silence des champs de betteraves, <Date>1998</Date>) and <Location>Ouarzazate</Location> the Movie (<Date>2001</Date>) to cite a couple of titles. He moved back to <Location>Morocco</Location> in <Date>2002</Date> and worked as an advisor to the <Origin>Moroccan</Origin> public television channel for three years. He now lives and works between <Location>Morocco</Location> and <Location>Brazil</Location>.
"

"Ali Jabri,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/j/jabri-ali</Address>
Born in <Location>Jerusalem</Location> in <Date>1942</Date>, Ali Jabri was seen as one of the leading Arab artists of his time.
From a family of prominent Syrians in <Location>Aleppo</Location>, Jabri was sent as a young man to study abroad, first at <Organization>Rugby School</Organization>, <Location>England</Location>, then to train as an architect at <Organization>Stanford University</Organization> in <Location>California</Location>. He later returned to study <Origin>English</Origin> literature at <Organization>Bristol University</Organization>,<Location>England</Location>, where he graduated in <Date>1970</Date>.
In <Date>1977</Date> he moved to <Location>Cairo</Location> where he began to work full-time as a professional artist. The drawings and sketch books included in Disorientation II were created during this important year when he both physically and intellectually journeyed back to the Arab world and began what would be a life-long fascination for, and investigation of, Arab culture, history and identity.By <Date>1978</Date> Jabri had settled in <Location>Amman</Location> where he lived until his death in <Date>2002</Date>. The richness of Arab culture and history inspired both Jabri’s art and his growing interest in the preservation of heritage sites and antiquities. He continued drawing and painting, while curating museum collections, participating in archaeological excavations, leading design and architecture projects at major antiquities sites, designing exhibitions and supervising other cultural heritage preservation projects. A large cache of previously unseen work, now conserved by the Ali <Organization>Jabri Human Heritage Foundation</Organization> in <Location>Amman</Location>, reflects the depth and diversity of his artistic oeuvre.
<Date>October 2010</Date>
"

"Almagul Menlibayeva,http://www.sharjahart.org/people/people-by-alphabet/m/menlibayeva-almagul</Address>
Almagul Menlibayeva has gained international recognition exhibiting at the 15th <Organization>Sydney Biennial</Organization>, the 51st, 52nd and 53rd <Location>Venice</Location> Biennales, MUHKA, <Location>Antwerp</Location>, <Location>Belgium</Location>, <Organization>Queens Museum</Organization>, <Location>New York</Location>, Herbert F. Johnson Museum, <Location>Ithaca</Location>, <Location>New York</Location>, <Organization>Stenersen Museum</Organization>, <Location>Oslo</Location>, the <Organization>University of California</Organization>, <Location>San Diego</Location>, Museo Universitario del Chopo, <Location>Mexico City</Location>, and Queensland Art Gallery, Bisbane. Menlibayeva&apos;s videos have been shown at the <Organization>Santiago International</Organization> Film Festival, <Location>Chile</Location>, and the Oberhausen and <Location>Rotterdam</Location> Film Festivals. She recently received a grant from the <Organization>Open Society Institute Budapest</Organization>, Art and Culture Network Program. She lives and works in <Location>Kazakhstan</Location> and <Location>Berlin</Location>.
"
